(
"ai_sub_version": "1.9.1",
"subtitles_prompt_version": 2,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": "gemini-cli:gemini-3-flash-preview",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true
),
"gemini_cli": (
"timeout": 600
)
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": true,
"fps": 1,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"encoder": "libx264"
)
),
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"subtitles": 8
),
"retry": (
"run": 3,
"max": 9,
"delay": 30
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": false,
"scrub": true
)
急遽！追加公演決定！
Urgent! Additional performance decided!
届いたレター　どっかの誰かがよかったのだろう
The letter that arrived, it must have been good for someone somewhere.
彼女が大事にしてた溜まった特大級のラブレター
The oversized love letters she cherished, piled up.
空を舞って　伝って　僕が拾う
Dancing in the sky, following along, I pick them up.
そんな運命道中を途中下車して　僕は僕の呼吸を重ねる
Getting off midway through such a path of destiny, I overlap my breaths.
長い長い旅　ゆっくりと進んでこう
A long, long journey, let's move forward slowly.
エルタマ お弁当 差し入れ企画 参加者一覧
本当にありがとうございました！
Eltama Bento Refreshment Project Participant List
Thank you very much!
なんでも解決してくれる時間って奴が相棒だから　息を吸って
Because the fellow called 'Time' who solves everything is my partner, take a breath.
長い長い旅
A long, long journey.
お腹減った　そろそろ
I'm hungry, it's about time.
焼きたてのパンの香りに思わず　カメもウサギに乗る
At the scent of freshly baked bread, even the turtle jumps on the rabbit's back.
街灯も瞬いて眠った
The streetlights flickered and went to sleep.
入れ替わり目を覚ました
Waking up in their place.
おーいもしもし　おーいもしもし
Hey, hello? Hey, hello?
ドキドキが奇跡　おーいもしもし
This pounding heart is a miracle, hey, hello?
はじまりはじまり　おーいもしもし
It's beginning, it's beginning, hey, hello?
おいしそう
Sounds delicious.
AZKi メジャー 1st アルバム Route If 配信中！
AZKi Major 1st Album Route If Now streaming!
青くて澄んだ空をぎゅっと抱きしめて
I hold the blue and clear sky tight,
今日も快晴だ
...and today is a beautiful day.
知らないはきっと　怖くて
Not knowing is surely scary,
分かるはきっと　安心できる
and understanding surely brings peace of mind.
でも私が選ぶのは　あり得ないの向こう側
But what I choose is the other side of the impossible.
青くて澄んだ空を
The blue and clear sky...
胸いっぱい吸い込んで
I breathe it in deeply.
透明になるまで
Until it becomes transparent,
声を鳴らして
...let my voice ring out.
私が誰かを照らせるなら
If I can illuminate someone,
誰かの救いになったら
...if I can be someone's salvation,
奇跡のひとつでも起こせるような気がするよ
I feel like I could even cause a miracle.
歌声は溶けて朝になる
The singing melts away and becomes morning.
悲しみ事抱いて微熱を帯びる
Embracing sadness, it takes on a slight fever.
そうだ
That's right.
この気持ちに名前つけるなら
If I were to give this feeling a name...
いつかはきっと　端から冷めて　定番になれば御の字
Someday for sure, if it cools down from the edges and becomes a standard, that's enough.
せっかくなら　みんなでさ　笑った顔を見せ合っていこうぜ
Since we're here, let's show each other our smiling faces together.
青くて旬な夢を　胸いっぱい背負い込んで
Shouldering a blue and seasonal dream with all my might,
揺れたその分だけ
...as much as it shook,
思い出となれ
...let it become a memory.
私が正し、幸せだったら
If I was right and happy,
悔やむことさえないから
...then I won't even have anything to regret.
心に眠る衝動に気づくこともないから
Because I wouldn't even notice the impulse sleeping in my heart.
歌声は涙に寄り添う
The singing nestles close to tears.
ときめき事抱いて微熱を帯びる
Embracing excitement, it takes on a slight fever.
そうだ
That's right.
この気持ちに名前つけるなら
If I were to give this feeling a name...
花が咲けば　零れてく
When flowers bloom, they spill over.
種を撒けば　宿ってく
When you sow seeds, they take root.
運命になんて　元から興味ないんじゃない？
Destiny? You weren't interested in that from the start, were you?
咲き誇れ　散り笑え
Bloom in full glory, fall with a laugh.
私が誰かを照らせるなら
If I can illuminate someone,
誰かの救いになったら
...if I can be someone's salvation,
奇跡のひとつでも起こせるような気がするよ
I feel like I could even cause a miracle.
歌声は溶けて朝になる
The singing melts away and becomes morning.
悲しみ事抱いて微熱を帯びる
Embracing sadness, it takes on a slight fever.
空が
The sky is...
温かくて綺麗だ
...warm and beautiful.
私はなんだか　小粋な
For some reason, I feel like this stylish...
この気持ちが愛おしくて　大好きだったんだ
...feeling is precious, I loved it so much.
名前のないこの気持ちを
To this nameless feeling...
快晴・修正・反映・構成　My Strategy
Clear sky, correction, reflection, composition - My Strategy
君と もっと一緒に行けるかな
Can I go even further together with you?
シチュエーション 誇動で どっちちのち
Which way is it with the heartbeat of the situation?
これこそが 高度な 情報戦
This is exactly what a high-level information war is.
完全安全 最前線 何でもかんでも 全開放
Completely safe, at the front line, everything is wide open.
改正修正 廃校正 マインストラテジー 次！
Revision, correction, abolition, main strategy, next!
反省の対象は 習慣生活の体であり
The subject of reflection is the state of habitual life.
して抜本の改正は 漫然や
And the fundamental revision is aimless.
万全の態勢は 冷静な理性に反して
A state of readiness goes against cool reason.
想定外 展開に 寧々々々が 渋滞中
In an unexpected development, the "Hey, hey"s are congested.
完璧なフェイントで クラクラリ
Dizzy with a perfect feint.
何でもっと 早く言ってくれないかな
Why couldn't you tell me sooner?
こんなんじゃダメでも 満身曖昧に
Even if this is no good, staying vaguely overwhelmed.
気づけばたすくことの 24時
Before I know it, it's 24:00 of "Task".
ジャストでエモい あっちこっち どっちがいいのかな
Just emotional, here and there, which one is better?
32分音符で クルクルシャッフル
Spinning and shuffling in 32nd notes.
ラグが もう少し どっちちのち
A little more lag, which way is it?
これこそが 高度な 情報戦
This is exactly what a high-level information war is.
教えてよ 有識者
Tell me, oh expert.
完全安全 最前線 何でもかんでも 全開放
Completely safe, at the front line, everything is wide open.
改正修正 廃校正 マインストラテジー 次！
Revision, correction, abolition, main strategy, next!
ここはどこ 私は誰 助けて
Where am I? Who am I? Help me.
色とりどり 寄り取り緑
Full of colors, picking and choosing.
選択肢は たくさんあるけど
There are many choices, but...
悩んでる時間が もう無理
Spending time worrying is no longer an option.
開店ダッシュで ストアだ
A dash to the store as it opens.
灰になっちゃって お亡牌になっちゃって
Turned to ash, turned to a dead tile.
消費する速度が
The speed of consumption is...
急いで走った分だけ
Just as much as I've run in a hurry.
寿命だって 早く来ちゃったりして
Maybe even my life expectancy will come sooner.
息切れして 声も出ないの
Out of breath, no voice comes out.
タイムパフォーマンス コストパフォーマンス
Time performance, cost performance.
言葉 踊り狂う 僕らって 盤の上
Words dancing madly, we're on top of the board.
毎日 焼かれて やり直しよ
Burned every day and starting over.
ランチタイム 泥濘 まったりさせて
Lunchtime, let me relax in the mud.
Woh-oh-oh ハートが欲しかない
Woh-oh-oh, my heart only has desires.
Woh-oh-oh さあさ 掘り込め
Woh-oh-oh, come on, dig in.
Woh-oh-oh 口の中が 溶けてゆく
Woh-oh-oh, the inside of my mouth is melting.
あれ？ ここはどこ 私は誰 助けて
Wait? Where am I? Who am I? Help me.
拝啓 石の上にも 三年もいられない者たちへ
Dear those who can't even stay on a rock for three years.
任せたっていい 辞めたっていい
It's okay to delegate, it's okay to quit.
量販店 還元 大バーゲン
Mass retailers, rewards, big bargains.
敵意維持 デフォルトね 閑散卵は至高のフェーズ
Hostility maintenance is the default, the silent egg is the supreme phase.
頑張るって 無駄のペイ 半信半礼
Trying hard is a waste of pay, half-belief and half-courtesy.
四季折々 風情 モリモリ
Seasonal charms, in abundance.
流れるのを 緩やかに 愛でて
Cherishing the flow gently.
味わいって 急がば回れ
To savor is to "more haste, less speed".
してるはずが 焦り 耳を凝らして
I should be, but in my impatience, I strain my ears.
泥になっちゃって 荒野になっちゃって
Turned to mud, turned to a wasteland.
摩耗する心が
My wearing-down heart...
削ぎ落として 脂肪分だけ
Stripped away of everything but the fat content.
痩せ細って 弱くなっちゃったりして
Maybe even becoming thin and weak.
息を捨て 声を出して
Letting out my breath, letting out my voice.
あれもしたい これもしたい
I want to do this, I want to do that.
そんな欲望 抱けるだけで 理想の人生
Just being able to hold such desires is an ideal life.
I see 悟り開いて オトナになっちゃって
I see, reaching enlightenment, becoming an adult.
腹八分目なんて まっぴら まっぴら ごめんなさい
Eat until 80% full? No way, I'm sorry.
タイムパフォーマンス コストパフォーマンス
Time performance, cost performance.
言葉 踊り狂う 僕らって 盤の上
Words dancing madly, we're on top of the board.
毎日 焼かれて やり直しよ
Burned every day and starting over.
ランチタイム 泥濘 まったりさせて
Lunchtime, let me relax in the mud.
Woh-oh-oh ハートが欲しかない
Woh-oh-oh, my heart only has desires.
Woh-oh-oh さあさ 掘り込め
Woh-oh-oh, come on, dig in.
Woh-oh-oh 口の中が 溶けてゆく
Woh-oh-oh, the inside of my mouth is melting.
あれ？ ここはどこ 私を探して
Wait? Where am I? Find me.
急遽！追加公演決定！
Urgent! Additional performance decided!
捕まえた でも逃げた
I caught it, but it got away
繰り返す本能には
In the repeating instinct
諦める術はない
There's no way to give up
無にさえも手を伸ばした
Extended a hand even to nothingness
だから強く見つめ合えば
So if we gaze strongly at each other
今を生き抜く術
The way to survive the present
描けそうで色のない
Faintly drawn, yet colorless
未来を避けた
Avoided the future
答えはわかんないよ
I don't know the answer
今は分岐は無限でも
Even if the branches are infinite now
君と交差したい時の果て
I want to cross paths with you at the end of time
期待値が高すぎたって
Even if expectations were too high
そこに追いついて
Catching up there
今はつまり何がどうだって
Now, no matter what's what
嘘は負ける 星が隠してしまう
Lies lose, the stars hide them away
綺麗な偽りを見抜いて
See through the beautiful lies
メジャー 1st アルバム Route If 配信中！
Major 1st Album Route If Now streaming!
紐解いた また増えた
Unraveled, increased again
残すしかない運命なら
If it's a fate that must be left behind
振り返る暇はない
There's no time to look back
闇よりも早い選択
A choice faster than the darkness
誰を満たす 誰かよりも
Satisfy someone, more than anyone else
まずは胸の中 凝視
First, gaze into the heart
黒い闇に星はただ
In the black darkness, stars just
輝きを真っ直ぐに届ける
Deliver their brilliance straight ahead
君はどう思うかな
What do you think?
今は全貌は知らないけど
Now, I don't know the whole picture, but
君と共鳴した 青い鼓動
The blue heartbeat resonated with you
揺らいでる境界の前で
In front of the swaying boundary
消えないように 吐露の本音
Lest it disappears, the true feelings exposed
今はいつのまにかでも
Now, even if it was before I knew it
嘘に染まる なんて無理だ
Impossible to be dyed in lies
これなら 届きそうで
With this, it seems reachable
これなら 遠くまで
With this, far away
信じて 信じて 信じたくて
Believe, believe, I want to believe
ここまでこれたから
Because I've come this far
壊れても 壊れても
Even if it breaks, even if it breaks
静かに小さな駆け引き
A quiet, small bargain
蘇る音 こんなに大事に感じるのは
The sound reviving, why it feels so precious
きっと君との絆だからね
Is surely because of our bond
今は分岐は無限でも
Even if the branches are infinite now
君と交差したい時の果て
I want to cross paths with you at the end of time
期待値が高すぎたって
Even if expectations were too high
そこに追いついて
Catching up there
今はつまり何がどうだって
Now, no matter what's what
嘘は負ける 星が隠してしまう
Lies lose, the stars hide them away
綺麗な世界で生きていた
I was living in a beautiful world
そんなの狡いのかな
I wonder if that's unfair
偽りを見抜いて
See through the lies
ああ 一言みたいな夜だ
Ah, it's a night like a single word
ばらまいた星だけが綺麗に澄んでいる
Only the scattered stars are beautifully clear
そんなに綺麗にはなれないや
I can't become that beautiful
それでも今夜 行くための歌
Still, tonight, it's a song to keep going
ああ ほんの小さな夜だ
Ah, it's just a small night
寝るには早く 夜明けはまだ遠く
Too early to sleep, the dawn is still far away
憧れるには遅く
Too late to yearn
挫けるにはまだ早いよ
Too early to give up
言葉はいつまでも下手だよ
I'm always bad with words
ため息だけが上手になるよ
I only get better at sighing
傷つくたび 違う
Every time I get hurt, it's different
生き物だと知るんだ
I realize I'm a living thing
いつだって 暗闇で迷子
Always lost in the darkness
明けない夜があったなら
If there was a night that never broke
このまま溶けて消えたいな
I'd want to just melt away and disappear like this
明けない夜があったって
Even if there was a night that never broke
私はきらめく星になれなくていい
I don't need to be a twinkling star
きらめく星になれなくていい
ああ 本日も閉店です
Ah, closed for today as well
どうにかこうにか一日
Somehow or other, a day
ひっそりこっそりよく頑張り
Quietly and secretly did my best
何かは残せたのでしょうか
I wonder if I left something behind
希望的だ
It's hopeful
差し入れを贈ってくださった開拓者の皆様、本当にありがとうございます！
To all the Pioneers who sent gifts, thank you so much!
差し入れをいただいた開拓者の皆様 本当にありがとうございます！
To all the Pioneers who gave gifts, thank you very much!
刹那的な
Ephemeral...
楽観的だ でも
Optimistic... but...
きっと美しいよ
It's surely beautiful.
痛いよ
It hurts...
良いよ
It's okay.
言葉はいつでも下手だよ
Words are always clumsy...
溜息だけが上手になるよ
...and only sighs become skillful.
傷ついて違う生き物だとして
Even if we're different creatures who get hurt...
それでも精一杯歌うよ
...I'll still sing with all my might.
泣きたい夜があったなら
If there's a night you want to cry...
笑えない夜があったなら
...if there's a night you can't smile.
溶けて消えてなくなって
Melting, disappearing, being gone...
きっともう一度ゼロから始めよう
...let's surely start again from zero.
明日のことは分からないや
I don't know about tomorrow...
昨日のことも知らないや
...and I don't know about yesterday either.
明けない夜があったって
Even if there's a night that never ends...
私は煌めく星になれなくていい
...it's okay if I can't become a sparkling star.
煌めく星になれなくていい
It's okay if I can't become a sparkling star...
そんな今夜素敵に生きるための歌
...this is a song for living wonderfully tonight.
窓の向こうを
Beyond the window...
星たちを
...the stars...
数えてたら
...as I counted them...
眠ってた
...I fell asleep.
その寝息と
With that sound of breathing...
ノイズが混ざる
...mixing with noise...
画面の向こう
...beyond the screen...
そばにいる
...I am by your side.
言葉なんてない
There are no words...
傷つくこともない
...and no getting hurt...
まるでね エトランゼ
...it's just like an etranger...
愛しくて
...so dear.
こんなにそばにいるのに
Even though I'm this close...
本当は遠い存在
...it's actually a distant existence.
伝えられた言葉が
The words that were conveyed...
涙になった フレーバー
...became a flavor of tears.
今日も頑張ってたんだね
You worked hard today as well, didn't you?
本当は手を差し伸べたい
I actually want to reach out my hand.
私の知らない
The you...
君のこと
...that I don't know.
どうすればいい
What should I do?
なんでもない
It's nothing...
何かすると
...if I do something...
崩れそう
...it might collapse.
独りここで
Alone here...
想いを馳せ
...lost in thought...
時間だけが
...only time...
過ぎてゆく
...passes by.
知らないうち
Before I knew it...
星は広がって
...the stars had spread out.
2024.7.24 リリース メジャー 1st アルバム 「Route If」
2024.7.24 Release Major 1st Album "Route If"
ワンマンライブ特典
Solo Live Bonus
君だけ
Only you,
君だけを
only you,
待っている
I am waiting for.
パノラマ
Panorama
いつか一緒に
Together someday
そう、特等席じゃなくても
Yeah, even if it's not a special seat
君と歌えるのならば
If I can sing with you
Na na na...
何も見えない空 よく似て
Much like the sky where nothing can be seen
ひどい顔で 撒き散らせる
With a terrible face, I can scatter it around
朝から世界で笑って
Smiling at the world since morning
誰も知らず 僕を壊す
Breaking me without anyone knowing
必死にしても 守れない約束
A promise that cannot be kept even with desperation
君に分かったんで
Since you understood it
もしもばかり 呟いてしまう
I keep muttering only "what ifs"
笑い疲れた 消えちゃいそうで痛いな
Tired of laughing, it hurts like I'm about to disappear
それでも無駄な小さい優しさ 止めてないよ
Even so, I haven't stopped those useless small kindnesses
忘れられないように 大人ぶって履いた
So as not to be forgotten, I put them on acting like an adult
嘘が 動き出して
Lies started moving
僕を 涙さえも
And even my tears
許されなくて 眠れない
Not being forgiven, I can't sleep
要らない心 重くかさばり動けない
The unneeded heart is heavy and bulky, I can't move
深くなる夜 僕と待ち合わせをした
The night deepens, I made a rendezvous with myself
上手く拭えない昨日 押し付けてまた回り
Pushing away the yesterday that can't be wiped well, it spins again
こんなんでごめん 諦めてないから 辛くて
Sorry for being like this, because I haven't given up, it's painful
諦めてないから 嫌ってく
Because I haven't given up, I'll come to hate it
正しさも分からず 手を引いて
Not knowing what's right, pulling the hand
誰も知らず 僕を壊す
Breaking me without anyone knowing
特別じゃない ただ普通でよかった
It's not special, just being ordinary was enough
褒めてあげてたら
If I had praised you
長く伸びた 前髪も好きになれた
I could have come to like my long bangs too
笑い疲れた 消えちゃいそうで痛いな
Tired of laughing, it hurts like I'm about to disappear
それでも無駄な小さい優しさ 止めてないよ
Even so, I haven't stopped those useless small kindnesses
忘れられないように 大人ぶって履いた 嘘が苦しい
So as not to be forgotten, the lies I told acting like an adult are painful
夢ねだりたい 楽しそうでいな 甘えれていな
I want to beg for a dream, look happy, be able to depend
なれない言葉を 拾いながら
While picking up words I'm not used to
明日へと並べ 当たり前じゃない朝が
Lining them up toward tomorrow, the morning that isn't ordinary
動き出して 僕を推した
Started moving and pushed me
涙さえも 許されなくて
Not even my tears are forgiven
眠れない
I can't sleep
AZKi メジャー 1st アルバム 「Route If」 レコメンドキャンペーン
AZKi Major 1st Album "Route If" Recommendation Campaign
ワンマンライブ特典：ライブ会場限定アクリルスタンドをプレゼント！
Solo Concert Perk: Venue-exclusive Acrylic Stand Giveaway!
急速! 追加公演決定! 2024.9.17 & 18 @ 豊洲PIT
Urgently Decided! Additional Concert! Sep 17 & 18, 2024 @ Toyosu PIT
スクリーンショットをSNSにアップロード投稿OK! 感想投稿OK!
Screenshots OK to upload on SNS! Impression posts welcome!
朝目覚めたミルク
Milk when I wake up in the morning
ホッとすれば
When I feel relieved
本当におめでとうございます！差し入れを送った開拓者の皆様
Congratulations! To all the Pioneers who sent refreshments
カップの中に地図みたいに広がる
Spreading like a map inside the cup
ミニチュアの秘密の世界旅行
A miniature secret world trip
なんてね
Just kidding
ゆっくり飲み干して
Drinking it all slowly
午後を迎えに行こう
Let's go meet the afternoon
少し読み進めた本
A book I've read a little
不意の花びら
An unexpected petal
栞の代わりに挟んで
Tucking it in like a bookmark
きっと次に開いたら
I'm sure when I open it next
その香りで
With that scent
物語が変わってる
The story will have changed
オレンジが滲む
Orange bleeds through
水面に
On the water's surface
止まない花の雨が波紋を
A rain of flowers that won't stop
作って不自然の一頁
Creates ripples on an unnatural page
めくったら新しい
When I turn it over, a new
季節かな
season perhaps
君と迎えに行こう
Let's go meet it with you
どんな毎日にしても
No matter what kind of day it is
ずっと先の
Because it's a story
自分の話だから
about my future self
特別を集めて
I'll collect the special moments
大きな束にしたいんだ
And turn them into a big bouquet
一緒にね
Together, okay?
おやすみの前には
Before saying goodnight
ホットワイン三日月のスパイス
Hot wine with crescent moon spice
ひと振り心の奥を
A dash of it to warm
温めて
the depths of my heart
星空見上げれば
When I look up at the starry sky
どこまでも飛び立つ
I'll take off anywhere
無限大の秘密の宇宙旅行
An infinite secret space trip
なんてね
Just kidding
ゆっくり夢を見て
Dreaming slowly
明日を迎えに行こう
Let's go meet tomorrow
息をしている
I'm breathing
だから生きている
That's why I'm alive
何度もずっと言葉を尽くしてきたんだ
I've been using all my words over and over
息をしている
I'm breathing
予報に見えている
Visible in the forecast
青が染み出す私にとっての何か
Something for me as the blue begins to bleed through
鼓動がドクドクしている
My heartbeat is thumping
ここはいつも変わらずに
This place remains unchanged as always
急かし続けるボタン一つの
Pushed by a single button that keeps hurrying me
いのち
Life
最後で私のこと覚えててくれるの
Will you remember me at the very end?
消えてしまいそうなの
It feels like I might disappear
分かってよ 分かってよ ねえ
Please understand, please understand, okay?
...の いつでも
...of, always
卒業するんでしょ
I'll graduate eventually, right?
日常に戻ったら
Once I return to daily life
私はいなくなるの
I will be gone
命のような
Just like a life
夢を見てるよ
I am dreaming
またね バイバイ
See you again, bye-bye
息をしてる
I'm breathing
だから生きてる
That's why I'm alive
見た目と中身の境界線を またいで戻って
Crossing and returning over the boundary
between appearance and reality
音が止まって 動かなくなって
The sound stops, and I become still
AZKi!
あ、光った流れ星　願いそびれ
Oh, a shooting star. I missed my chance to make a wish,
もう一回を待った
and waited for another one.
あっという間に夜が明け
In a blink, the night turned into dawn.
もういいや　このまんま散歩しよう
Oh well, I'll just go for a walk like this.
あ、横切った野良猫　色は黒
Oh, a stray cat crossed my path. It's black,
でも可愛いから優勝
but it's cute, so it wins.
パン屋さんが開くのは7時
The bakery opens at seven.
あと10分　何しようかな
Ten minutes left. What should I do?
お守り　もしもし　亀さんよ
A charm. Hello, Mr. Turtle.
今だけは　キミになりたい
Just for now, I want to be like you.
ピョンって跳んだ　ウサギさん
Mr. Rabbit went hop,
ひょんな事　氷河降る日に出会う
and by chance, we meet on a glacier-falling day.
理屈だって　合ってないようなもんで
Logic is like something that doesn't quite fit.
ファンタジー　浮かべ
Floating in a fantasy,
今日もニヒル
nihilistic again today.
そこの街灯すらも　意外と僕が
Even that streetlight over there,
イヤフォン外したら　歌い出す
unexpectedly starts singing when I take off my earphones.
冬にだけ可視化される声の温度が
The temperature of a voice, visible only in winter,
春や夏や秋はどこへと　消えてしまうのか
where does it disappear to in spring, summer, and autumn?
きっとそこにある
It's surely right there.
触れる　揺らぐ
Touching, swaying.
気づいて　気づいてって
Saying "Notice me, notice me."
まるで心の中みたい
Just like inside my heart.
冬にだけ可視化される声の温度が
The temperature of a voice, visible only in winter,
春や夏や秋は誰かに　届いてるのかな
does it reach someone in spring, summer, and autumn?
だってここにある
Because it's right here.
消える　消える
Disappearing, disappearing.
暑さも　寒さも
The heat and the cold,
全部ちょうどいいの前触れ
all just a prelude to being just right.
わぁ！
Whoa!
瞬間　風が吹いた
In an instant, the wind blew.
予報外の煽りが
An unforecasted gust.
儲かったの？
Did you gain anything?
だよ
That's right.
彼女が大事に溜めてた　特大級の溢れた
An extra-large overflow she'd been carefully saving.
空を待って　伝って
Waiting for the sky, tracing it,
僕が拾う
I'll pick it up.
そんな運命待ち途中下車
Getting off halfway while waiting for such a fate.
僕は　僕の呼吸を重ねる
I overlay my breath with mine.
まばたきを止めて
Stop blinking,
ゆっくりと進んでこう
and let's move forward slowly.
何でも解決してくれる時間ってやつが相棒だから
Because time, the thing that solves everything, is my partner.
息を吸って
Take a breath.
まばたきを止めて
Stop blinking.
お腹減った　そろそろ
I'm getting hungry about now.
出来立てのパンの香りに思わず
Without thinking, at the scent of freshly baked bread,
亀もウサギに乗る
even the turtle hops on the rabbit.
街灯も瞬いて眠った
The streetlights flickered and fell asleep.
入れ替わり目を覚ました
Waking up in their place,
通り達　もしもし
the streets. Hello.
星召し
Stars summoning.
ドキドキ　は　奇跡
Pounding hearts are a miracle.
星召し
Stars summoning.
始まり　始まり　おしるし
It begins, it begins, a sign.
行くよ、開拓者！
Let's go, pioneers!
愛が言葉を蒸し返してる
Love is rehashing words,
空が涙を降らせていたんだ
the sky was letting tears fall.
誰のために
For whose sake?
何のために
For what purpose?
これが運命だというの
Is this what you call fate?
嘘が街を包み込んでい
Lies are enveloping the town,
鳥が飛べずに声を上げていた
birds unable to fly were raising their voices.
ただ一つの存在を灯す
Lighting up just one existence,
この場所で君を待ってる
I'm waiting for you at this place.
世界はとても苦しそうでした
The world seemed very painful.
私に何ができるというの
What can I possibly do?
歌うことが正しいかなんて
Whether singing is the right thing to do,
今も答えは見つからないけど
I still haven't found the answer, but...
大丈夫、みんながいる
It's okay, everyone is here.
私はここにいるの
I am right here.
何回何十回だって　君と出会うから
No matter how many dozens of times, I'll meet you again.
夜が明けていく
The night is breaking,
光が降り注ぎ
light is pouring down.
喜び悲しみを抱え前を向く
Holding onto joy and sorrow, looking forward.
君と生きてく
I'll live with you,
この場所で
at this place.
それが私の世界だ
That is my world.
その一秒一瞬が煌めく
That one second, that one moment, sparkles.
イェーイ
Yay!
過去が虹を壊したとしても
Even if the past destroyed the rainbow,
夢が街を喰らい尽く...
even if dreams devour the town...
たとえ世界が悲しみに溢れたとしても
Even if the world is filled with sadness,
大丈夫だから
It'll be okay,
そばにいるよ
I'll be by your side.
君に笑ってほしいんだ
I want you to smile.
今生まれた君を探しているの
I'm looking for you, who was just born.
転んでもただ走り続けていく
Even if I fall, I'll just keep on running.
今を知って明日を投げた
Knowing the present, I cast away tomorrow.
心が叫びたがってる
My heart wants to scream.
タイムマシンに乗ってさ
If I could take a time machine
別の未来を選ぶことができたなら
and choose a different future,
君のいない世界を想像する
imagining a world without you—
そんな世界は想像できない
I can't imagine such a world.
届いてるよね？
It's reaching you, right?
この声がこの歌が
This voice, this song...
何回何十回だって君を選ぶから
No matter how many times, I'll choose you.
夜が滲んでいく水平線の彼方へ
Towards the horizon where the night blurs,
響く鼓動の音を
The sound of my echoing heartbeat,
確かに感じた
I certainly felt it.
始めよう君との未来を
Let's start our future together.
繋いだ手を離さないで
Don't let go of my hand.
大きな声で名前を呼んで
Call out my name with a loud voice.
奇跡を駆け抜けて
Run through the miracle,
どこまでもいけるよ
we can go anywhere.
ここからもう一度
From here, once more
君と私で始めよう
let's start together, you and me.
無限の中に生まれた物語を
The story born within the infinite,
君とどこまでも
forever with you.
この世界が悲しみに溢れたとしても
Even if this world is filled with sadness,
私は歌を歌い続けていく
I will keep on singing my song.
君と生きるここでこの場所で
Living with you here, in this place,
それが私の世界だ
that is my world.
その一分一秒が煌めく
Every minute, every second sparkles.
Yeah
傷つき涙を流す君が
I pray that the world becomes a place
幸せだと思える世界になりますように
where you, who are hurt and shedding tears, can feel happy.
願いを込めて歌う
I sing with a prayer in my heart.
ありがとう
Thank you.
私最強で最弱な
I'm the strongest and the weakest,
弱気な心をスーツで隠して
hiding my timid heart with a suit.
正体はいつも負けない
My true self never gives up.
強い私でいさせてよ
Let me be my strong self.
いくぞ、横浜！
Let's go, Yokohama!
今日も一日スマートにライド
Another day of riding through smartly,
人をすり抜け早歩きステーション
slipping through the crowd and walking fast to the station.
タスク処理して定時で帰るの
Processing tasks and heading home on time,
ビール飲み干して爆睡寝るだけ
draining a beer and just falling into a deep sleep.
みんなが思ってるような
Since when did I start acting
私を演じたのはいつから？
the way everyone expects me to?
わかんなくなってぐちゃぐちゃになっても
Even if I get confused and everything becomes a mess,
信じていたい
I want to keep on believing.
私最強で最弱な
I'm the strongest and the weakest,
弱気な心をスーツで隠して
hiding my timid heart with a suit.
正体はいつも負けない
My true self never gives up.
強い私でいさせてよ
Let me be my strong self.
鏡に映る私を
Looking closely at the person
じっと見つめる最強最弱
reflected in the mirror—strongest, weakest.
毎日飛び乗り通勤
Hopping on for the daily commute,
ノマドもリモートなんのその
don't care about nomads or remotes.
評価気になり辛くても
Even if caring about evaluations is tough,
明日はきっと笑えてる
I'll surely be laughing tomorrow.
信じて信じて何度裏切られても
Believing, believing, no matter how many times I'm betrayed,
何度だって立ち上がれる
I can stand up over and over again.
私は最強最弱だ
I am the strongest and the weakest!
みんなが思ってるような
I am not someone who belongs
私はいて誰のものでもないの
to anyone, despite what everyone thinks.
わかんなくなってボロボロになっても
Even if I get confused and worn out,
立ち続けたい
I want to keep on standing.
私最強で最弱なガール
I'm the strongest, yet weakest girl
私最強で最弱なガール 弱音吐いて泣き叫びたい時だって
I'm the strongest, yet weakest girl,
even when I want to voice my weakness and cry out
弱さ捨てられない 弱い私愛させてよ
I can't throw away my weakness,
let me love my weak self
私最強で最弱なガール 弱気な心が空を撃って隠して
I'm the strongest, yet weakest girl,
my timid heart shoots and hides the sky
最後はいつも負けない 強い私愛させてよ
In the end, I never lose,
let me love my strong self
鏡に映る私が じっと見つめ返してくる
The me reflected in the mirror stares back intently
強くありたいと願うの 少しずつ知ってる 最強最弱さ
I wish to be strong,
I'm learning little by little, this strongest-weakest self
みんなー！こんあずきー！
Everyone! Kon-AZKi!
右手にマイク、左手に地図、あなたのハートをゼロゲッサー！
Mic in my right hand, map in my left,
I'm the GeoGuesser of your heart!
バキュン！バズン！バゴーン！
Pew! Bam! Kaboom!
はい！ということで始まりました！
AZKi Major Debut LiVE「声音エントロピー」
Yes! And so it has begun!
AZKi Major Debut LiVE "Kowairo Entropy"
昼の部、みんな来てくれてありがとう！
Day Performance, thank you everyone for coming!
ということで、もうちょっとすごい、もう最初やって、
もう感極まっているんですけれども...
So, it's already amazing, just having done the first part,
I'm already overcome with emotion...
なんと現地は4年7ヶ月ぶりです！
Unbelievably, it's been 4 years and 7 months
since the last live venue performance!
今日、この日を一緒に迎えてくれて本当にありがとうございます！
Thank you so much for welcoming
this day together with me today!
もう泣きそう！待って待って、もうすでにヤバい！
I'm about to cry! Wait, wait, this is already crazy!
まだこんな序盤なのに、序盤なのに！
Even though it's still so early, so early in the show!
はい、ということで、今日はですね、生バンドを迎えて、
Yes, and so, today we have a live band,
声と音とみんなの想い、一体感のあるライブにしたいなと思ってます！
and I want to make this a live performance where voice,
sound, and everyone's feelings are as one!
ありがとう！
Thank you!
会場のみんなも、そして配信で見ているそこの君も、
Everyone here at the venue, and you there watching the stream,
ペンライトを持って一緒に盛り上がってください！
please hold your penlights and let's get excited together!
よろしく！わー、すごい！
Please! Wow, amazing!
ということで、今日のハッシュタグ、
So, for today's hashtag,
#AZKiワンマン横浜昼 でぜひね盛り上げていただけると嬉しいです。
よろしくお願いします！
I'd be happy if you could help trend the show today
using #AZKiワンマン横浜昼. Please look forward to it!
そしてそして、先日リリースしました、
And also, the song that was released the other day,
みんな「Route If」は聴いてくれましたかー？
did everyone listen to "Route If"?
はい、その曲も今日はやっていきたいと思いますので、
Yes, I'd like to perform that song today as well,
ぜひぜひ最後まで、あとね、あとね、あのね...
so please stay until the end, and also, and also, you see...
昼と夜でセトリ全然違うんだよー！
The setlist is completely different
for the day and night performances!
ということでセトリにも注目してぜひ見ていってください。
So please pay attention to the setlist as well.
そして、ここで無料配信は終わります！
And here, the free stream will end!
YouTubeでチラ見せ枠が今ね配信されているんですが、
The "peek frame" is currently being streamed on YouTube,
この先はぜひ配信チケットをゲットしてお楽しみください。
but from here on, please get a streaming ticket and enjoy.
ということで国内向けはSPWNにて、
So, tickets are now on sale at SPWN for Japan,
海外向けはStreaming+にて、チケット発売中ですので、
ぜひ最後まで見てほしいなと思います。よろしくお願いします！
and Streaming+ for overseas. I hope you'll watch
until the very end. Thank you!
みんなどう？ライブ楽しい？楽しい？楽しい？
How is it, everyone? Are you enjoying the live show?
Enjoying it? Enjoying it?
みんなそう言ってくれるとAZKiもとっても、とってもとっても楽しいです！
When you say that, AZKi also has a lot, a lot a lot of fun!
ということで、じゃあ行っちゃいますか。次は「Route If」から！
And so, shall we get going? Next up is "Route If"!
この曲です！
This is the song!
Pa pa, pa-pa-pi-ya
起きたて　手に入れた紅茶
Freshly made tea in my hands
朝の光
Morning light
お砂糖代わりに　浮かべて
Floating in place of sugar
揺らす　今日の始まりは
Stirring it, today's beginning
ちょっと特別
Is a little special
そんな気持ちに　なるんだ
That's how it makes me feel
あたためたミルク
The warmed milk
落とせば
When I pour it in
カップ中に　地図みたいに広がる
Spreads like a map inside the cup
ミニチュアの秘密
A miniature secret
冒頭無料はこちらで終了です。
The free preview ends here.
本編続きをご視聴されたい方は、SPWNにてご購入お願いします。
If you wish to watch the rest, please purchase it on SPWN.
冒頭無料はこちらで終了です。
本続きをご視聴されたい方は、SPWNにてご購入お願いします。
The free preview ends here.
If you wish to watch the rest, please purchase a ticket on SPWN.